Let's talk about analyzing metrics.
我们现在讲分析指标
Earlier, we touched on one component of our analytics process and that was analyzing,
上一个视频里 我们提到了市场分析流程 其中一个步骤就是分析
but we've only scratched the surface.
但我们只是很浅显地提及到了
When it comes to analyzing data,
其实数据分析是一个非常深奥的概念
a true methodology by which we want to look at these insights.
从数据里获取见解 有一整套的方法论
Now the skill of drawing information out of
从数据集里提取有用信息其实很大程度上
our datasets is often going to be the result of experience.
依赖于经验
As you spend more time with the data,
数据经验越丰富
you'll get more comfortable at finding
越能从不同的数据点里
connections between all of these different data points.
发现联系
But simply being curious,
但是 作为初学者 保持好奇心
having an outside the box way of thinking,
跳出框框思维来思考
and figuring out how to see the bigger picture is a great place to start.
思考如何看到数据背后更广阔的世界 这些就很好
Analyzing the marketing metrics tells us what is
只有正确地开展了数据分析工作 我们才能从市场指标的分析里
happening but only if we do our analysis properly.
得出有关市场的有用信息
Now it's just as likely you'll do a bad analysis on good data
你的数据很好 但有可能分析很烂
as it is you'll do a fantastic analysis on bad or suspect data.
也有可能数据很烂 但是分析很棒
It's actually rarely the case that the data itself is bad,
其实大多数时候 数据是无所谓好坏的
but rather the way the data is interpreted.
你如何分析这些数据 才会是好的 或者坏的
For example, it's easy to mix up a visit and a pageview.
比如 用户访问 (a visit) 和页面浏览 (pageview) 就是很容易混淆的概念
A visit is one person arriving whereas
用户访问是指一个用户访问了某个页面
a pageview is something that happens every time a page loads.
而页面浏览是每一次的页面加载
A visitor can have many pageviews.
一个用户访客可以有很多页面浏览
Think about a visitor to our grocery store.
比如超市和顾客
They come in and they could look at many products,
顾客走进超市 逛商品
but that one person has looked at many things.
一个顾客可以逛很多个商品
If we instead accidentally modeled our conversion rate on
如果我们在计算转化率的时候
how many products were looked at versus how many people purchased,
不小心将分母设置成了顾客看过的商品数量 而不是购买了商品的顾客数量
we'd have a really unrealistic view of what's happening.
我们的数据分析就非常不准确了
So the metrics that you use need to be accurate.
所以我们的分析指标一定要准确
You need to be using the right data and the right data points.
你需要用正确的数据以及正确的数据点
Also, in our analysis process,
同时 在分析的时候
all of these metrics must be compared.
必须比较这些指标
So we start with them being accurate,
确保了指标正确之后
and then we think about how we compare them.
我们再来看如何比较
Comparison is important because without it,
比较是必要的 如果不比较的话
the metrics will really provide no sense of direction.
指标就没有意义了
So in order to generate a comparison,
所以为了能比较
we look at change and context over time.
我们需要看看过往数据
In other words, how does this metric change during
即 这些指标在过去的一段时间里如何变化
a period of time and what is the context of that change?
以及产生这些变化的背景原因
Is it normal or abnormal?
这些变化是正常还是不正常？
So I want to give you an example.
我来举个例子
Let's say that we open up our store and there are no visitors.
比如 我们的超市今天正常营业 在某个时段还没有任何顾客
The first thing that we have to do is compare that.
首先 我们要来比较一下
So if you look to yesterday,
先看看昨天的情况
is zero less than yesterday or more than yesterday for that same window of time?
在昨天同样的时段 我们有更多的顾客还是更少的顾客
If we opened up the story yesterday and we had
如果今天比昨天少 比如昨天同样的时段 有 3 个顾客
three visitors and today we have zero, well,
而今天一个顾客都没有
now we know that the change is we have three less visitors during this same time period.
那么我们就知道 今天比昨天 在同样的时段 少了 3 个顾客
Now we have to ask is that normal or abnormal?
接下来要问 这个变化是正常的还是不正常的？
To do that, we might have to zoom out.
要判断这个 我们要来看看更多的过往数据
We might need to look at a trend over time.
我们需要看过去一段时间内的数据
Do we typically have a lot of visitors in the morning?
早上通常有很多顾客吗？
Is today different from other days?
今天和其他日子有什么不一样？
Perhaps today is a Saturday and most people aren't coming in this early on a Saturday.
可能因为今天是星期六 大多数人在星期六都不会这么早来
So we have to look at the context,
所以 要知道某个变化是否正常
we have to zoom out to really understand whether that change is normal or abnormal.
我们需要抽身出来 从更大的全局根据历史数据来看
Analyzing the data is an exercise that's oftentimes like being a detective.
分析数据有时候就像做一名侦探一样
So remember, when you analyze your metrics,
记住 分析指标的时候
you always want to start with accurate metrics.
首先要确保指标是正确的
From there, you need to compare them.
然后比较这些指标表现 00:03:19,069 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 要看历史数据和背景原因